<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./rest-delete.png"
        type="Manipulator"
        xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
        xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
        xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>DELETE Request</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        DELETE REST client
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        <p>This node can be used to issue HTTP DELETE requests. DELETE requests are used to delete resources on a server.
        Usually you don't send any data with the request and you also don't get anything back, except for maybe a
        status message. Although sending additional data with a DELETE request generally has no defined semantics,
        some HTTP service implementations may still use this. Hence, a request body can be attached in this node as well.</p>
        
        <p>The node allows you to either send a request to a fixed URL (which is specified in the dialog) or to a list of
        URLs provided by an optional input table. Every URL will result in one request which in turn will result in one
        row in the output table. You can define custom request headers in the dialog.</p>
        <p>The sent data is usually taken from a column of the input table but you can also provide a constant value
        in the dialog instead.</p>
        <p>By default the output table will contain a column with the received data, its content type, and the HTTP 
        status code. The node tries to automatically convert the received data into a KNIME data type based on its
        content type. In case no automatic conversion is possible, binary cells will be created.<br />
        You can extract additional response headers into column by defining them in the dialog.</p>
        <p>The node supports several authentication methods, e.g. BASIC and DIGEST. Other authentication methods may be
        provided by additional extensions.</p>
        
        <p>
        The node supports the Credential port as input (see dynamic input ports). If the port is added, it must supply a
        Credential that can be embedded into the HTTP Authorization header, and all request done by the node will
        use the Credential from the port, regardless of other node settings. The OAuth2 Authenticator nodes provide
        such a Credential for example.
        </p>

        </intro>
        
        <tab name="Connection">
            <option name="URL">Select a constant URL or a column from the input table that contains the URLs that you
            want to request.</option>
            <option name="Handling of invalid URLs">Specifies how invalid URLs are handled. Depending on the selected mode,
            this node either inserts missing values as responses, fails the node execution on encountering the first invalid URL, 
            or omits such rows from the output. The latter option filters rows based on URL validity of the URL column. 
            For REST client nodes, all URLs conforming to <a href="https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc1738">RFC 1738</a> 
            and using the HTTP or HTTPS protocol are considered valid.</option>
            <option name="Delay (ms)">Here you specify a delay between two consecutive requests, e.g. in order to avoid
            overloading the web service.</option>
            <option name="Concurrency">Number of concurrent requests</option>
            <option name="Ignore hostname mismatches">If checked, the node trusts the server's SSL certificate even if
            it was generated for a different host.</option>
            <option name="Trust all certificates">If checked, the node trusts all certificates regardless of their
            origin or expiration date.</option>
            <option name="Follow redirects">If checked, the node will follow redirects (HTTP status code <tt>3xx</tt>).</option>
            <option name="Send large data in chunks">
                Specifies whether HTTP Chunked Transfer Encoding is allowed to be used by the node. If enabled, messages
                with a large body size are being sent to the server in a series of chunks.
            </option>
            <option name="Connect timeout (s)">The connection timeout is the timeout in making the initial connection. 
                In case of HTTPS, this includes completing the SSL handshake. This timeout is set in seconds.</option>
            <option name="Read timeout (s)">The read timeout is the time to wait until the first byte of data is read.
                Increasing this timeout makes sense if you have a slow connection or you expect the server will take a 
                long time to prepare your response. This timeout is set in seconds.</option>
            <option name="Body">Name of the response body column in the output table</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Authentication">
            <option name="Type">The authentication type, e.g. no authentication, BASIC, or DIGEST</option>
            <option name="Use credentials">Uses the selected credentials instead of username and password provided in the dialog.</option>
            <option name="Username">The username used for authentication.</option>
            <option name="Password">The corresponding password used for authentication.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Proxy">
            <option name="Direct connection (no proxy)">
                This option disables the proxy for this DELETE node. This will bypass KNIME-wide proxies as well.
            </option>
            <option name="Use KNIME-wide proxy settings">
                Uses the same proxy as the KNIME platform. In the KNIME Analytics Platform, this can be changed under 
                <tt>File > Preferences > General > Network Connections</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="Use node-specific proxy settings">
                This option enables the configuration fields in the "Proxy" tab. 
                The proxy settings apply only to this DELETE node.
            </option>
            <option name="Proxy Protocol">
                This option describes the proxy protocol to use. HTTP, HTTPS and SOCKS can be selected.
            </option>
            <option name="Proxy Host">
                Specifies the proxy host address.
            </option>
            <option name="Proxy Port">
                Specifies the port that should be used at the proxy host.
            </option>
            <option name="Workflow Credentials">
                If enabled, this option allows to select credentials stored in the workflow to be used for the username and password.
                Filling the "Username" and "Password" fields is not needed then.
            </option>
            <option name="Username">
                If the option "Proxy host needs authentication" is enabled, this field specifies the username to use. 
                Always uses <tt>Basic</tt> authentication for proxy hosts.
            </option>
            <option name="Password">
                If the option "Proxy host needs authentication" is enabled, this field specifies the password to use. 
                Always uses <tt>Basic</tt> authentication for proxy hosts.
            </option>
            <option name="Excluded Hosts">
                If the option "Exclude hosts from proxy" is enabled, this field specifies the hosts that will be ignored by the proxy connection.
                Requests to excluded hosts will use a direct connection. If multiple hosts are specified, they should be separated using a vertical bar ('|').
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Error Handling">
            <option name="Fail on connection problems (e.g. timeout, certificate errors, …)">
                This option describes what should happen if there was a problem establishing the connection to the
                server. The node either fails in execution or outputs status code and error message in the corresponding
                row.
            </option>
            <option name="Server-side errors (HTTP 5XX)">
                These options describe what should happen if a response with a 5XX status code is received. These
                status codes usually describe errors on the server side.
            </option>
            <option name="Client-side errors (HTTP 4XX)">
                These options describe what should happen if a response with a 4XX status code is received. These status
                codes usually describe client-side errors such as an incorrect web address.
            </option>
            <option name="Fail node execution or output missing value">
                This option describes what should happen after a request has failed. The node either fails in execution
                or outputs a missing value in the row of the output table that corresponds to this request. This option can
                be set separately for server- and client-side errors.
            </option>
            <option name="Retry on error">
                Specifies whether the node should retry a request if the initial request received a response indicating
                a server-side error.
            </option>
            <option name="Number of retries">
                The maximum number of retries to perform for server errors (count does not include the initial request).
            </option>
            <option name="Retry delay">
                The delay to apply between the first request and the first retry. For each subsequent retry, the delay
                is doubled.
            </option>
            <option name="Rate-limiting error (HTTP 429)">
                This status code can be returned by a server to indicate that the rate of incoming requests has been too
                high.
            </option>
            <option name="Pause execution">
                In case of a rate-limiting error, wait for the set amount of time before retrying the request. Note that
                this delay is static and does not increase with subsequent attempts, neither does it count as retries
                for server-side errors.
            </option>
            <option name="Output additional column with error cause">
                If enabled, each output row corresponding to a request will contain an additional cell that, in case
                the request has failed, will provide a description of the error cause. If the request was successful, the
                cell will contain a missing value.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Request Headers">
            <option name="Merge">If you click this button the request headers from the selected template on the left are
            merged with the already existing header definitions in the table below.</option>
            <option name="Replace">If you click this button the request headers from the selected template on the left will
            replace any existing header definitions in the table below.</option>
			<option name="Header key">The HTTP header key, e.g. <tt>Accept</tt> or <tt>X-Custom-Key</tt>. Note that some
			header keys such as <tt>Origin</tt> are silently ignored by default for security reasons. You can configure
			KNIME AP to allow any header key by setting the <tt>sun.net.http.allowRestrictedHeaders</tt> system property in the
			<i>knime.ini</i> configuration file to <tt>true</tt>.</option>
            <option name="Header value">The value for the header which can be a constant value or a reference to a flow
            variable, a column, a credential name, or a credential password (see the kind option).</option>
            <option name="Header kind">The kind of the value specified, which is either a constant value or a reference
            to a flow variable, a column, a credential name, or a credential password.</option>
            <option name="Fail on missing header value">Setting this option makes the node fail once a header input value is not 
            available anymore, e.g. due to a missing value. Is enabled by default.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Request Body">
            <option name="Use column's content as body">Use the selected column's content as the body of the request.</option>
            <option name="Use constant body">Use the specified content below as the body of the request.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Response Headers">
            <option name="Extract all fields">If checked, all header fields present in the first response are extracted
            into columns.</option>
            <option name="Header key">The name of the header to extract.</option>
            <option name="Header type">The KNIME data type the header should be converted into.</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Table">Optional data table containing the variable parameters of the requests.</inPort>
        <dynInPort insert-before="1" name="Credential"
            group-identifier="Credential">
            A Credential, that can be embedded into the HTTP Authorization header. If this port is added,
            then all request done by the node will always use the Credential from the port, regardless of other
            node settings. The OAuth2 Authenticator nodes provide such a Credential for example.
        </dynInPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="DELETE results">Data table containing columns from the responses.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
